<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on recogito.github.io</title>
    <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on recogito.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:28:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://recogito.github.io/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Firebase for Storage</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/using-firebase-for-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:28:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/using-firebase-for-storage/</guid>
      <description>Using Firebase for Storage A quick and easy way to set up your own annotation store without managing your own server is through Firebase, a web application development platform by Google. Firebase includes a cloud-based document database with a JavaScript SDK for storing, updating and deleting JSON records. All you need to do is wire up the Firebase storage SDK operations with the corresponding events from Annotorious.
Using Events for Storage When Annotorious fires the createAnnotation event, store the annotation via the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing UI Translations</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/contributing-ui-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 20:04:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/contributing-ui-translations/</guid>
      <description>Contributing UI Translations We want to make our software available in as many languages as possible. If you want to help: providing a translation is easy - and because there are not many labeled user interface elements, it&amp;rsquo;s also not a lot of work.
Message Dictionaries The user interface labels are part of the recogito-client-core package, located here. In this folder you will find messages files, one file for each available translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/development-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:46:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/development-setup/</guid>
      <description>Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Annotorious and RecogitoJS We welcome pull requests to Annotorious and RecogitoJS - both to the code, as well as to our documentation! To contribute, simply fork the relevant repository and hack away.
Repositories &amp;hellip;
Developing  Clone the repository Run npm install to download project dependencies Run npm start to launch the project in dev mode, with hot-reloading enabled Go to http://localhost:3000/  Building a distribution bundle  Run npm run build to build a distribution bundle The distribution files will be in the dist folder  Want to find your way around in the source code?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>