<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Guides on recogito.github.io</title>
    <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Guides on recogito.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:28:19 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://recogito.github.io/guides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Firebase Storage</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/using-firebase-for-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 13:28:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/using-firebase-for-storage/</guid>
      <description>Using Firebase for Storage A quick and easy way to set up your own annotation store without managing your own server is through Firebase, a web application development platform by Google. Firebase includes a cloud-based document database with a JavaScript SDK for storing, updating and deleting JSON records. All you need to do is wire up the Firebase storage SDK operations with the corresponding events from Annotorious.
Annotorious Lifecycle Events When Annotorious fires the createAnnotation event, store the annotation via the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extending the Editor</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/extending-the-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 14:24:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/extending-the-editor/</guid>
      <description>Extending the Editor Per default, the Annotorious/RecogitoJS editor popup features two widgets:
 A comment widget for writing comments and replies A tag widget for adding tags, either freetext or supported by a pre-configured vocabulary and an autosuggest dropdown  You can can customize this setup when you initialize Annotorious/RecogitoJS using the widgets config option. The configuration below will give you the editor shown in the image above.
var anno = Annotorious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing Appearance</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/customizing-appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 10:47:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/customizing-appearance/</guid>
      <description>Customizing Visual Appearance Need a different look and feel? Customizing the visual appearance of Annotorious is easy! All elements of the annotation layer and the editor window can be styled with CSS.
Customizing the Annotation Layer Annotorious renders annotations using SVG, which means you can completely alter the visual appearance of every graphical element via CSS.
To make styling even more flexible, Annotorious adds a few extras:
 For every annotation shape, Annotorious renders two SVG shapes, exactly on top of each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing Translations</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/contributing-ui-translations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 20:04:18 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/contributing-ui-translations/</guid>
      <description>Contributing UI Translations We want to make our user interface available in as many languages as possible. If you want to help: providing a translation is easy - and because there are not many labeled elements, it&amp;rsquo;s not a lot of work.
Message Dictionaries The user interface labels are part of recogito-client-core, a JavaScript package for common code shared between Annotorious and RecogitoJS. In this folder you will find messages files, one file for each available translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker&#39;s Guide</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/development-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 11:46:22 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/development-setup/</guid>
      <description>Hacker&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Annotorious and RecogitoJS We welcome pull requests to Annotorious and RecogitoJS - both to the code, as well as to our documentation! To contribute, simply fork the relevant repository and hack away. Our code is located in the following repositories
 recogito/recogito-client-core. A base module that contains most of the code for RecogitoJS, and all code that is shared between RecogitoJS and Annotorious. You&amp;rsquo;ll need this module if you want to hack anything about RecogitoJS (text selection, relationship drawing) or the common editor popup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Custom Widgets</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/guides/creating-custom-widgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 20:56:23 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/guides/creating-custom-widgets/</guid>
      <description>Creating Custom Editor Widgets  Please note that this guide is still under construction.
 The editor popup is shared between Annotorious and RecogitoJS. It is possible to extend it with your own widgets. To write your own editor extensions, you should familiarize yourself with some basics first:
 The W3C Web Annotation concept of annotation bodies Editor widgets and how they relate to annotation bodies  Annotation Bodies In the terminology of the W3C Web Annotation spec, an annotation consists of multiple bodies - data structures that each represent one &amp;ldquo;piece&amp;rdquo; of the annotation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>