<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on recogito.github.io</title>
    <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on recogito.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:10:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenSeadragon Plugin</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/osd-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/osd-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with the OpenSeadragon Plugin The OpenSeadragon plugin is an extension to the OpenSeadragon viewer for zoomable high-resolution images. Click the annotation to edit. Hold SHIFT while clicking and dragging the mouse to create a new annotation.
 .openseadragon-canvas { outline:none; background-color:#f4f4f4 !important; border-radius:3px; }        var sampleAnnotation = { &#34;@context&#34;: &#34;http://www.w3.org/ns/anno.jsonld&#34;, &#34;id&#34;: &#34;#07475897-d2eb-4dce-aa12-ecb50771c734&#34;, &#34;type&#34;: &#34;Annotation&#34;, &#34;body&#34;: [{ &#34;type&#34;: &#34;TextualBody&#34;, &#34;value&#34;: &#34;Annotation&#34; }], &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation Model</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:33:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>The W3C Web Annotation Model Annotorious supports the W3C Web Annotation model, an open standard for interoperable annotations on the web. However, only a part of the specification is supported at the moment. Current limitations are:
 Only annotations with a single rectangle shape are supported The W3C Media Fragments FragmentSelector is the only supported selector type Annotation TextualBody types with a purpose of commenting, replying or no purpose are displayed as comments Anntation bodies with a purpose of tagging are displayed as tags Bodies of any other type are ignored (unless you implement your own editor extension)  { &amp;#34;@context&amp;#34;: &amp;#34;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing Annotations</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/storing-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/storing-annotations/</guid>
      <description>Storing Annotations To store annotations, you need an annotation server or database backend. Annotorious - as well as its sister project RecogitoJS - do not include their own storage solution. They provide the user interface functionality for annotation only. To store annotations, you need to connect them to your own backend, using the API.
When the user creates, updates or deletes an annotation, Annotorious emits the following events:
 createAnnotation updateAnnotation deleteAnnotation  Subscribe to these events, and execute the corresponding write operations to your backend.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
