<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on recogito.github.io</title>
    <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on recogito.github.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:10:57 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>OpenSeadragon Plugin</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/osd-plugin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/osd-plugin/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with the OpenSeadragon Plugin The Annotorious OpenSeadragon plugin is an extension to the OpenSeadragon viewer for zoomable high-resolution images. Click or tap the annotation to edit. Hold the SHIFT key while clicking and dragging the mouse to create a new annotation.
Download the latest release and include script and stylesheet file in your web page. Make sure to include the script after the OpenSeadragon script.
&amp;lt;!-- CSS stylesheet --&amp;gt; &amp;lt;link rel=&amp;#34;stylesheet&amp;#34; href=&amp;#34;annotorious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Annotation Model</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/web-annotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 14:33:09 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/web-annotation/</guid>
      <description>The W3C Web Annotation Model Annotorious supports a subset of the W3C Web Annotation model, an open standard for interoperable annotations.
Only a single target shape per annotation is supported. FragmentSelectors of type Media Fragment are supported for rectangle shapes (see example below), with both pixel- and percent-encoded coordinates. SVG Selectors aer supported for polygon shapes (see example below). Annotation TextualBody types with a purpose of commenting, replying or no purpose are displayed as comments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storing Annotations</title>
      <link>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/storing-annotations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 10:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://recogito.github.io/annotorious/getting-started/storing-annotations/</guid>
      <description>Storing Annotations Important: Annotorious does not provide a backend for storing annotations online. It provides user interface functionality only. To store annotations, you need to connect them to your own backend, using the JavaScript API.
When users create, update or delete annotations, Annotorious emits the following events:
createAnnotation updateAnnotation deleteAnnotation Subscribe to these events, and execute the corresponding write operations to your backend.
anno.on(&amp;#39;createAnnotation&amp;#39;, function(annotation) { // This part depends entirely on how your backend works axios.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
